Finding Aid for the American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California Records LSC.0900
UCLA Library Special Collections
American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California records
circa 1935-1985
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0900
736 linear feet (1513 boxes, 3 oversize boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California, 1967. Accruals from the ACLU of Southern California were transferred to UCLA Library in 1968, 1969, 1970, 1973, 1974, 1977, 1980, 1985, 1986, 1990, and 1991.
Gift of Eason Monroe, 1966-69.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994621353606533
Biographical / Historical
The American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) was established in 1920. It originally began as the American Union Against Militarism in 1915 and later became the National Civil Liberties Bureau in 1917. The ACLU of Southern California was established in Los Angeles in 1924.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of legal, educational, and organizational files of the American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California. Includes minutes, correspondence, memoranda, clippings, case files, and briefs. Topics covered in case files include the right to counsel, women's rights, Japanese-American relocation during WWII, blacklisting in the film industry, and Crawford vs. LA Unified School District. Also contains materials related to the local and national organizations of the ACLU.
Related Materials
Safeguarding civil liberties [oral history transcript] / Eason Monroe, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1972. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
American Civil Liberties Union Archives (MC #001) Available at Princeton University Library.
The National ACLU Archives, 1917-1946 (approximately) are available on microfilm through Interlibrary Loan from University of Wisconsin Library.
For an index to the archives see: Baskin, Alex | American Civil Liberties Papers, a guide to the records of the ACLU, 1912-1946.
- General civil liberties
  - Articles -- 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Censorship and boycott -- 3, [2 folders.] (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Censorship Panel - Workpapers/Minutes (1955): Censorship press releases (1955- 1958). (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers - Magazines -- 4, [2 folders.] (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Foreign publications -- 4.1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pornography -- 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Comics -- 6 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - One-party press -- 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Books -- 8 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Art -- 9 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Motion pictures -- 10 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Storm Center -- 10.1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Radio - TV -- 12, [4 folders.] (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
  - Blacklisting -- 13, [3 folders.] (Box 2, Folder 9-10, Box 3)
  - Post office non-delivery -- 14 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bishop G. Bromley Oxnam - Philharmonic Auditorium -- 17.1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Free speech
  - Free speech -- 18, [2 folders.] (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Public meetings - Speech permits -- 19 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Handbill legislation -- 21 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Censorship Committee -- 22, [2 folders.] (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Fillibuster -- 23 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Libel -- 24 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Campaign libel -- 24.1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Proposition 24 (1962) -- 28, [3 folders.] (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
- Internal security
  - Internal security -- 30, [2 folders.] (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Security programs -- 31, [2 folders.] (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Attorney General's list -- 31.1, [2 folders.] (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Foreign agents -- 31.2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Federal government's security program -- 32, [2 folders.] (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Harry Cain -- 32.1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Alger Hiss -- 32.4 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pension denial -- 32.5 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - General investigations -- 33 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bi-partisan Security Commission of 1955 (WRIGHT) -- 34 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Loyalty - Wright Security Commission -- 34 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Senator Johnston's investigations of 1955 -- 35 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Military forces -- 36, [2 folders.] (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Radulovich -- 37 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Slobodin -- 38 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Civilian government employees -- 39 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Ladejinsky -- 40 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Oppenheimer -- 41 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fort Monmouth -- 42 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Workers in private industry needing U.S. government clearance -- 43 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Federal government licensees -- 44 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Edward Lamb -- 45 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - States other than California - Security vs. Right to work -- 46 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - California - Right to work vs. Loyalty oaths, etc. -- 47 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - State security laws other than California -- 47.1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Los Angeles City / County - Security vs. Right to work -- 48, [2 folders.] (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Paul Orr (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chester Weger (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Private industry's own program -- 50 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Private groups - Security vs. Right to work: Barring own members (attorneys, unions) -- 51, [2 folders.] (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Civil liberties and 1961 California State Legislature -- 51.2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Public housing - Gwinn Amendment (national) -- 52 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Public housing - Gwinn Amendment (Los Angeles) -- 53 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - J.E. Hoover (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Smith Act -- 54, [4 folders.] (Box 7, Folder 3-6)
  - Conspiracy-to-advocate cases -- 55 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - California cases - Smith Act -- 56 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - California Smith Act cases - Briefs -- 57, [2 folders.] (Box 7, Folder 9, Box 8)
  - Party-member cases -- 58 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Steve Nelson -- 58.1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - State sedition laws and other acts against Communist Party -- 59 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Braden Case -- 60 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - California sedition laws -- 61 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous government attacks on communists -- 62 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Culver City Reds -- 63 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Communist Control Act of 1954 -- 64 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Internal Security Act (1950) - McCarran Bill -- 65, [2 folders.] (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board -- 66 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Taft-Hartley non-communist oaths -- 67 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Immunity Bill -- 68 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Rosenbergs -- 70 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Sedition (Powell case) -- 70.1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sobell -- 70.2 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
  - Barrenblatt Decision -- 70.5 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Immigration & naturalization
  - Immigration and naturalization -- 71 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952 (Walter-McCarran Act) -- 72, [4 folders.] (Box 9, Folder 6, Box 10)
  - Statements by Southern California candidates -- 73 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Legislative changes (Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952) -- 74, [2 folders.] (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
  - President's Commission -- 74.1 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Kilgore Hearings -- 75 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Immigrants -- 76 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Temporary visitors -- 77 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Aliens -- 78 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Deportation cases -- 78.1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Five Spanish Sailors Case -- 78.2 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - David Hyun -- 79 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Diamond Kimm -- 79.1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Wixman -- 80 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - John Juhn -- 81 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Denaturalization -- 82 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bridges -- 83 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Tokyo Rose -- 83.1 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Native-born denaturalization -- 84 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Passports -- 85, [2 folders.] (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
- Academic freedom
  - Academic freedom -- 86, [4 folders.] (Box 12, Folder 3-6)
  - AAUP censured administrations -- 86.1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - California Senate Education Committee -- 87 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Teachers -- 88 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Teachers -- 88 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Attacks on teachers and inquiries -- 88 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ione Swan -- 88.1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Florence Sloat Case -- 88.2 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - California teachers -- 89 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Loyalty oaths -- 90 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Loyalty oaths - Schools -- 90 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Loyalty tests -- 90 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Oaths of Allegiance of different states (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - (California teachers) Credentials -- 91 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - St. John's Case -- 92 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Wendell Phillips -- 92.1 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Steinmetz -- 93 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Right to participate in politics -- 93 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Students -- 96 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - UC - Student regulations -- 96.1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Un-American Committee (California) Dec.'56 UCLA (Student's death) -- 96.1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - UCLA students -- 96.1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Berkeley - Students -- 96.2 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Riverside / Lessin Case -- 96.3 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Educational materials -- 97 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - L.A. book banning, screening, etc. -- 98 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Teaching about Communism -- 99 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - UNESCO controversies -- 100 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - L.A. School Board --101 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Project: L.A. Board of Education (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Dilworth Act -- 102 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Parochial school tax exemption -- 109.1 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Medicine and religion -- 109.2 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Church and state -- 110, [2 folders.] (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - Propositions 5 & 6 -- 111 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Tax exemption -- 112 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Churches - Tax exemption -- 113 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Solicitation for religious purposes -- 113 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Church loyalty oath court cases -- 114 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Veterans loyalty oath -- 115 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Teaching religion in schools -- 115.1 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Released time -- 116 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - School property for religious use -- 117 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Bible reading in schools -- 120 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Religious holidays celebrated in public schools -- 121 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Nuns teaching in public schools -- 122 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Religious protection laws / adoption -- 123 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Freedom of belief and practice -- 124 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Inter-religious marriages -- 124.1 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Nudism -- 125, [2 folders.] (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
  - Citizenship-pacifists -- 126 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Homosexuality -- 127 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - One, Inc. -- 127.1 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Communism in religion -- 128 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Jehovah's witnesses -- 129 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Militarism -- 130 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - UMT -- 131 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Military code and POW's -- 132 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Peace -- 133 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Disarmament -- 134 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Legislative committees
  - Legislative committees in general -- 135 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Favorable critiques -- 136 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Unfavorable critiques -- 137 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Legislative changes in procedure -- 138 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Hennings' Hearings -- 138.5 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee -- 139, [2 folders.] (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee - Southern California hearings -- 139.1 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Wheeldin-Dawson -- 139.2 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Senate Internal Security Committee -- 140 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Owen Lattimore -- 141 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Senate Subcommittee on Government Operations -- 142 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - McCarthy -- 143 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Attacks by McCarthy -- 143 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Personal attacks on McCarthy - Recall Movement, etc. -- 143 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Statements attacking McCarthyism -- 143 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Statements on the effects of McCarthyism -- 143 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Leroy Gore -- 144 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - O'Connor and Emspak - 1st Amendment -- 145 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Other states un-American committees -- 146 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - California State Senate Un-American Activities Committee -- 147 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Fifth Amendment policy statements -- 149 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Non-communist cases and 1st Amendment -- 149.1 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 1st Amendment and Wilkinson -- 149.2 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Informers -- 150 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Matusow -- 151 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Judicial processes
  - Judicial processes -- 152, [3 folders.] (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Mental illness and due process -- 152.2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Capital punishment -- 153 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Capital punishment - Gottlieb -- 153 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Capital punishment - Gottlieb, Mosk, Eason Munroe -- 153 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Habeas corpus -- 154 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - California vagrancy law -- 154.1 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Mentally ill -- 154.2 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Exclusionary Rule of Evidence -- 155 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Cahan Case -- 155.1 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Jenck's Case / FBI files -- 155.2 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Military courts -- 156 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Shibley Case -- 156.1 (Box 22, Folder 9-10)
  - Right to counsel -- 157 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Trial by newspaper -- 158 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Perjury charges, etc. when statute of limitations has expired for actual crime -- 159 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Felon registration -- 159.1 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Grand jury -- 160 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Priestly -- 160.1 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Cross-examination rights -- 161 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Property - Due process -- 161.1 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Juvenile due process -- 161.2 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Attacks on Supreme Court -- 161.3 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Improper police & FBI practices
  - Improper police and FBI practices -- 162, [2 folders.] (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
  - L.A. Police -- 162.1 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Wiretapping and bugs -- 163 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Brutality -- 164, [2 folders.] (Box 23, Folder 7, Box 24)
  - Bonding cops -- 164.1 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Police Review Board -- 164.2 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Fingerprinting -- 165 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Registration requirements -- 165.1 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Japanese-American relocation - WWII -- 166 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Forced confessions -- 167 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Mexican-American undocumented workers -- 168 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Illegal entry and/or search and seizure -- 169 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Lawless Law Enforcement Committee -- 169 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Military police -- 170 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Illegal imprisonment -- 171 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Police education -- 172 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - The FBI -- 172.1 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Police block system - Mass roadblocks -- 172.2 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Labor
  - Labor -- 173 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Organized labor - General -- 173 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - 1959-60 Congress: Labor reform -- 173 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Organized labor - Development of unity moves -- 173 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Organized labor - Attack on -- 173 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - History of labor -- 173.1 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Right to make political contributions -- 174 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Political activity -- 174.1 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Time off for voting -- 174.2 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Internal union democracy -- 175 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Right to work - ACLU defense -- 176 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Right to work - NAM defense -- 177 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Right to organize -- 178 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Right to organize - New vendors -- 178 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Right to organize - Police union -- 178 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Picketing -- 181 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Strikes -- 182 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Race
  - Taft-Hartley Act -- 182.1 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Race -- 182.5, [2 folders.] (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
  - Truman's Civil Rights Commission -- 182.6 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Civil Rights Act -- 182.7 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Anthropological articles -- 183 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Racism -- 184, [2 folders.] (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
  - Race as a political issue -- 184.1 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Congressional proposals (1959) -- 184.2 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Civil Rights Act (1957) -- 184.21 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Superior Court and civil rights -- 184.3 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Racism and Christianity -- 184.4 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Bigots and prejudice -- 185 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Negro -- 186 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Anti-Semitism -- 187 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Mexican-Americans -- 188 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Southern states -- 190 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Ku Klux Klan -- 190.1 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Sumner, Mississippi - Till killing -- 196.1 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Capital integration -- 203 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Northern states -- 204 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - California state law on civil rights -- 205 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Negroes in L.A. -- 206 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Intergroup relations agencies of cities -- 207 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Biased legal cases -- 208 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Extradition -- 208.1 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Discrimination in employment -- 209 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Discrimination in government contracts -- 209.1 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Nixon Commission -- 209.2 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Discrimination in employment cases -- 210 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - L.A. Fire Department -- 211 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - F.E.P. progress -- 212 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - F.E.P. progress - California -- 213 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - F.E.P.C. reports -- 214, [2 folders.] (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
  - Armed forces discrimination -- 215 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Integration in neighborhoods -- 216 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Fair housing -- 216 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Fair housing -- 216 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Fair housing -- 216 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Housing and land ownership -- 216 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Housing and land ownership -- 216 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Oyama v. California -- 217 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Garden Grove, California -- 217.2 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Education -- 218, [2 folders.] (Box 30, Folder 7-8)
  - Supreme Court decision -- 219 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Progress and/or lack of implementation of School Segregation Decision [Desegregation/Integration] -- 219.1 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
  - De facto school segregation -- 219.2, [2 folders.] (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
  - Federal aid to schools -- 220 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - El Centro Case -- 221 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Public accommodations -- 222 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Public accommodations discrimination cases -- 222 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Racial identification in press -- 222.1 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Southern Pacific Case -- 223 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Race equality - Discrimination-Segregation - Covenants -- 224 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Discrimination by private organizations -- 224 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Interracial marriage -- 224.1 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Discrimination in religion -- 225 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Discrimination in medicine -- 226 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Discrimination in labor -- 227 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Discrimination in voting -- 228 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - American Indians -- 229 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Women's rights -- 230 (Box 32, Folder 12)
- United Nations
  - United Nations -- 231 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Internal affairs and statements concerning the United Nations -- 231 (Box 32, Folder 14)
- Foreign nations
  - Africa -- 232.1 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Far East -- 232.2 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Italy -- 232.3 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - South East Asia (Burma, Malaysia, Australia, etc.) -- 232.4 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - India & Pakistan -- 232.5 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - China (Mainland) -- 232.6 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Korea -- 232.7 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Germany -- 232.8 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Israel -- 232.9 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - England -- 232.10 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous -- 232.11 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Bricker Amendment -- 233 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - South Africa -- 235 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - U.S.S.R. -- 235.4 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Initiative and referendum -- 236 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Communism -- 237 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Schools -- 238 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - COPE (Committee on Public Education) -- 238.1 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - U.S. economy -- 239 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Foreign policy - Big Four Negotiations also Big Three -- 239.1 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Smog -- 240 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Atom Bomb and H-Bomb (Statements, tests, reactions) -- 240.5 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Welfare aid -- 241 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - UAW -- 242 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Automation -- 243 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Atomic power, etc. -- 243.1 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Tariffs & Free Trade Situation -- 244 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - L.A. County Charter (City & County affairs) -- 245 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Voting and Legislative reapportionment (1953 Bi-elections) -- 245.1 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Hawaii / Alaska -- 245.2 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Veterans Affairs -- 245.3 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Virgin Islands -- 245.4 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Housing situation -- 245.6 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Eisenhower Administration -- 245.7 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Attacks on Eisenhower Administration -- 245.7 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Arts Division (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Censorship material (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Status of LACC chapter (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - San Gabriel Valley (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Church-state Committee, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - ACLU v. Board of Education of San Diego, etc. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - ACLU of Southern California v. Board of Education of Los Angeles (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Bill and cases pending (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - ACLU court decisions (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Machinists' case (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Wendell Phillips (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - 66: A.L. Wirin Cases (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - A.L. Wirin court analysis (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Wirin's radio programs (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Integration in Los Angeles city schools (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Women's committee education workshop (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Lawyers workshop dinners, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - National legislation (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - House Un-American Committee (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Wiretapping (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Community relations conference (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Fair employment practice commission (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Police brutality (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Police practices committee, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Francis amendment (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Governor's committee on constitutional rights (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Operation womanpower (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Income/expense statements, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Special fund raising (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. A-F, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. A-F, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. A-F, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. A-F, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. A-F, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. A-F, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Statements, receipts, etc. G-Z, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 12)